{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The phospholipids present in cytoplasm membrane of the archaeo-bacteria is", "opta": "phosphoglycerides", "optb": "polyisoprenoid", "optc": "polyisoprenoid branched chain lipids", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oldest eukaryotic organisms are considered to be", "opta": "diplomonads like Giardia", "optb": "archaea", "optc": "fungi", "optd": "animals", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The phospholipids present in cytoplasm membrane of eubacteria is mainly", "opta": "phosphoglycerides", "optb": "polyisoprenoid", "optc": "phospholipoprotein", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which were the investigators lived at the same time?", "opta": "Koch and Pasteur", "optb": "Darwin and Woese", "optc": "Van Leeuenhoek and Ricketts", "optd": "Berg and Hooke", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unifying feature of the archaea that distinguishes them from the bacteria is", "opta": "habitats which are extreme environments with regard to acidity", "optb": "absence of a nuclear membrane temperature", "optc": "presence of a cell wall containing a characteristic outer membrane", "optd": "cytoplasmic ribosomes that are 70S", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mycoplasmas are different from the other prokaryotes by", "opta": "presence of chitin in cell walls", "optb": "presence of murrain in cell walls", "optc": "presence of proteins in cell walls", "optd": "absence of cell wall itself", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Evolutionary relationships between groups of organisms are determined using which of the following type of information?", "opta": "Comparisons of nucleotide sequences", "optb": "Comparisons of biochemical pathways", "optc": "Comparisons of structural features", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true for eukaryotic cells?", "opta": "Nucleus is bounded by nuclear membrane", "optb": "Chromosomes contain histones", "optc": "Chloroplasts and mitochondria contains 70S ribosomes", "optd": "Gas vacuoles are present", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true for prokaryotic organism?", "opta": "Nucleus is not bounded by nuclear membrane", "optb": "Chromosomes does not contain histones", "optc": "80S ribosomes are distributed in cytoplasm", "optd": "Cell wall contains peptidoglycan as one of the major component", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gram staining was introduced by", "opta": "Christian gram", "optb": "Alfred Gram", "optc": "Robertcook", "optd": "Louis Pasteur", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is considered the most unifying concept in biology?", "opta": "Taxonomy", "optb": "Anatomy", "optc": "Genetics", "optd": "Evolution", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Various bacterial species can be subdivided into", "opta": "subspecies", "optb": "biovarieties", "optc": "serovarieties", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Living organisms have many complex characteristics. Which one of the following is shared by non-living matter as well?", "opta": "Homeostasis", "optb": "Tissues", "optc": "Reproduction", "optd": "Molecules", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A newly discovered microscopic structure is hypothesized to be a living organism. Which of the following lines of evidence would support the contention that this organism may be alive?", "opta": "It contains DNA", "optb": "It is made of a single cell", "optc": "It utilizes energy", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mycoplasmas, rickettsiae, and chlamydiae are", "opta": "types of fungi", "optb": "small bacteria", "optc": "species of protozoa", "optd": "forms of viruses", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following structure is absent in eukaryotic cells?", "opta": "Mitochondria", "optb": "Chloroplasts", "optc": "Golgi structure", "optd": "Mesosome", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Who was the inventor of the Petri dish?", "opta": "R.J. Petri, an assistant of R. Koch", "optb": "A famous French cook", "optc": "Italian glass blower from Petri, Italy", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one is not studied in microbiology?", "opta": "Bacteria", "optb": "Animal behaviour", "optc": "Fungi", "optd": "Algae", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A characteristic of protein synthesis in both the archaea and eukarya is", "opta": "transcription and translation are coupled", "optb": "translation is inhibited by diphtheria toxin", "optc": "proteins are synthesized from D-, rather than L-, isomers of amino acids", "optd": "the initiator tRNA is charged with N-formyl-methionine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cell theory includes all of the following except", "opta": "all organisms are composed of one or more cells", "optb": "the cell is the most primitive form of life", "optc": "the cell is the structural unit of life", "optd": "cells arise by division of preexisting cells", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The five-kingdom system of classification was set up by", "opta": "Louis Pasteur", "optb": "Robert Whittaker", "optc": "Robert Koch", "optd": "Masaki Ogata", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The membranes of which domains are chemically the most similar?", "opta": "Archaea and Bacteria", "optb": "Bacteria and Eukarya", "optc": "Eukarya and Archaea", "optd": "membranes of all three domains are chemically identical", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Primary differences between cilia and flagella are", "opta": "arrangement of microtubules", "optb": "length and location of basal bodies", "optc": "how the microtubules are fused to each other", "optd": "number, length and direction of force", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All membranes of free-living organisms have phospholipid bilayers, but exception is", "opta": "bacteria", "optb": "fungi", "optc": "archaea", "optd": "protozoa", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All of the following are features of prokaryotes except", "opta": "nitrogen fixation", "optb": "photosynthesis", "optc": "sexual reproduction", "optd": "locomotion", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following structures is the smallest?", "opta": "Viriod", "optb": "Hydrogen atom", "optc": "Bacterium", "optd": "Mitochondrion", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is/are included in Kingdom Prokaryotae?", "opta": "Bacteria", "optb": "Protozoa", "optc": "Fungi", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following may account for the small size of the cells?", "opta": "The rate of diffusion", "optb": "The surface area/volume ratio", "optc": "The number of mRNAs that can be produced by the nucleus", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Genetic and biochemical similarities between contemporary cyanobacteria and eukaryotic chloroplasts are accepted to mean that", "opta": "eukaryotes evolved from bacteria", "optb": "eukaryotes evolved from archaea", "optc": "oxygenic photosynthesis first evolved in eukaryotes", "optd": "cyanobacteria arose from chloroplasts which escaped from plant cells", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best represents the hierarchy of levels of biological classification?", "opta": "Phylum, kingdom, class, order, genus, species, family", "optb": "Kingdom, phylum, class, order, family, genus, species", "optc": "Kingdom, phylum, family, class, order, genus, species", "optd": "Class, order, kingdom, phylum, family, genus, species", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The three domain version of life on earth is based on the", "opta": "nucleic acid sequence data", "optb": "morphological traits", "optc": "metabolic traits", "optd": "characteristics of the cell wall", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The foundation for the germ theory of disease was set down by", "opta": "Robert Koch", "optb": "Ronald Ross", "optc": "Louis Pasteur", "optd": "Walter Reed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most microbial structures and enzymes are composed of", "opta": "lipids", "optb": "proteins", "optc": "carbohydrates", "optd": "lipids and carbohydrates", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The individual best remembered for bringing microbes to the world is", "opta": "Robert Hooke", "optb": "Antony Van Leeuenhoek", "optc": "Robert Koch", "optd": "Masaki Ogata", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Micro organisms are found in which of the following kingdom of five kingdom concept (Whittaker's classification)?", "opta": "Monera", "optb": "Protista", "optc": "Fungi", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first organism in most natural food chains is", "opta": "a herbivore", "optb": "a decomposer", "optc": "photosynthetic", "optd": "carnivorous", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The third kingdom, protista, as suggested by E.H. Haeckel includes", "opta": "bacteria", "optb": "algae", "optc": "fungi", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Eukaryotic cell organelles first emerged", "opta": "from a specialized lineage of cells within the kingdom Protista", "optb": "when prokaryotes engulfed each other and became interdependent", "optc": "when bacteria made their first attempts at reproduction", "optd": "just before the origin of the animal and fungal kingdoms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Who discovered the bacteria that cause cholera?", "opta": "Pierre Berthelot", "optb": "Robert Koch", "optc": "Louis Pasteur", "optd": "Rudolf Virchow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Prokaryotic microorganism include", "opta": "protozoa", "optb": "fungi", "optc": "bacteria", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All the following are basic properties of cells except", "opta": "cells have nuclei and mitochondria", "optb": "cells have a genetic programme and the means to use it", "optc": "cells are capable of producing more of themselves", "optd": "cells are able to respond to stimuli", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following microorganisms is classified as a member of archaebacteria?", "opta": "Gyanobacteria", "optb": "Methanobacteria", "optc": "Trichomonads", "optd": "Mycoplasma", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The idea of selective toxicity was first proposed by", "opta": "Antony van Leeuwenhoek", "optb": "Paul Ehrlich", "optc": "Louis Pasteur", "optd": "Alexander Fleming", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following sequences has helped in identifying eukaryotes, eubacteria and archeabacterial cell types?", "opta": "Signature sequence", "optb": "Signal sequence", "optc": "Shine-Dalgarno sequence", "optd": "Amino acid sequence", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Archeal cells usually do not contain peptidoglycan, rather contain pseudo-peptidoglycan which is mainly composed of", "opta": "N-acetylmuramic acid and L-amino acids", "optb": "N-acetylmuramic acid and D-amino acids", "optc": "N-acetyltalosaminuronic acid and D-amino acids", "optd": "N-acetyltalosaminuronic acid and L-amino acids", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the three domain system of classification, the traditional bacteria are placed in the", "opta": "eukarya", "optb": "archaea", "optc": "eubacteria", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of the reasons for the evolutionary success of the kingdom Monera is that its members are nutritionally diverse. Which of the following(s) is/are the way(s) of obtaining energy?", "opta": "Photoautotrophy", "optb": "Photoheterotrophy", "optc": "Chemoheterotrophy", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Carl Woese and his colleague are best known for establishing", "opta": "the five kingdom system", "optb": "the three domain system", "optc": "the prokaryote-eukaryote system", "optd": "the plant-animal system", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not found in the kingdom Monera?", "opta": "Organelles", "optb": "Organized cell structure", "optc": "Ability to reproduce", "optd": "Ability to use energy", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the most primitive?", "opta": "Virus", "optb": "Eukaryote", "optc": "Archaeon", "optd": "Mitochondria", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All the following are considered eukaryotes except", "opta": "archaea", "optb": "fungi", "optc": "protozoa", "optd": "humans", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which cell type is considered to have the oldest ancestor?", "opta": "Archaea", "optb": "Bacteria", "optc": "Eukarya", "optd": "they all share the same ancestor", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is Mycology?", "opta": "Study of viruses", "optb": "Study of nucleic acid", "optc": "Study of bacteria", "optd": "Study of fungi", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organelles contain DNA, divides and possesses some degree of autonomy?", "opta": "Golgi apparatus", "optb": "Ribosome", "optc": "Chloroplast", "optd": "Peroxisomes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All of the following individuals contributed to cell theory except", "opta": "Robert Hooke", "optb": "Matthias Schleiden", "optc": "Theodor Schwann", "optd": "Rudolf Virchow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Eukaryotic micro organisms include", "opta": "protozoa", "optb": "fungi", "optc": "algae", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binomial name of a microbe is composed of", "opta": "its kingdom and genus names", "optb": "its genus name and a species modifier", "optc": "its family and class names", "optd": "its genus and species names", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a characteristic unique to the ciliates?", "opta": "Use of cilia as a sensory function", "optb": "Presence of both a macronucleus and several micronuclei", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Possess a light-detecting eye spot", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following structure is present in prokaryotic cells?", "opta": "Mitochondria", "optb": "Chloroplasts", "optc": "Golgi structure", "optd": "Mesosome", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The word cell was first used by", "opta": "Robert Hooke", "optb": "Theodor Schwann", "optc": "Louis Pasteur", "optd": "Ronald Ross", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are Blue-Green bacteria called?", "opta": "Acquaobacteria", "optb": "Cyanobacteria", "optc": "Protozoa", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The endosymbiosis hypothesis provides an explanation for how", "opta": "eukaryotes developed from prokayotes", "optb": "prokaryotes developed from eukaryotes", "optc": "algae developed from protozoa", "optd": "protozoa developed from algae", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Archaea include all of the following except", "opta": "methanogens", "optb": "halophiles", "optc": "thermoacidophiles", "optd": "cyanobacteria", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}